Okay, here's
the situation.
Your parents went away
on a week's vacation.
They left the keys to
the brand new Porsche.
Would they mind?
Well, of course not.
(SINGING) /'/ just take
it for a little spin
And maybe show it
off to a couple of friends
TH just cruise
around the neighborhood
Well, maybe | shouldn't
Yeah! Of course | should
Pay attention, here's
the thick of the plot
Pulled up to the corner
at the end of my block
That's when |
saw this beautiful
girly-girl walking
! picked up my car phone
To perpetrate
like | was talking
Sunroof was open,
the music was high
And that girls
hand was steadily
moving up my thigh
She had opened
up three buttons
on her shirt so far
! guess that's why
! didn't notice
that police car
l can't believe it!
l made a mistake
But parents are the same
No matter time nor place
So to all you
kids all across the land
No need to argue
Parents just
don't understand
JERRY: Yeah!
DONNA: AlI right!
(BOTH APPLAUDING)
Thank you. Thank you.
Just a little
something | know.
So, what's up?
Someone is on
fire in Ramsett Park.
They need you to get
down there right away.
Oh, my God.
l've been spending
the summer doing
a lot of zoo promotions.
(SINGING) For he's
a jolly good fellow...
Parrots live
a very long time.
So we had a birthday party
for a parrot that turned 60.
(SINGING) ...which
nobody can deny
Chimpanzees are very
smart, so we had them
graduate from college.
And they like to fling
their feces, so we were
hoping that they
would fling their hats.
But they just
flung their feces.
(SCREECHING)
The Pawnee Zoo
recently purchased
two South African
black-footed penguins,
Tux and Flipper.
And as part of our
zoo promotion,
we are going to give them
a marriage ceremony,
because they
mate for life.
Tux, do you take
Flipper, to be your
lawfully wedded wife?
ldo! | do!
By the power
vested in me from
the Department of
Parks and Recreation,
l now pronounce
you husband and wife!
(WEDDING MARCH PLAYING)
Oh!
Okay, well,
at least they're married.
Are they making babies?
Well, not those two.
Those are both boy penguins.
l'm sorry?
Tux and Flipper
are both boys.
So you should
have pronounced them
husband and husband,
technically.
That's awesome.
Still, you couldn't
have asked for
better weather.
Brendanawicz,
you big sandwich eater.
Oh...
Cut it out, now.
Just to be clear,
that was a friend punch.
There was
no flirtatious
meaning behind
that playful punch |
just gave your arm.
Yes, | do understand.
You've made it
abundantly clear
that there's no
romantic element
to our relationship
in any way.
Yes. Good. Isn't it
good to be able to just
kind of horse around
like this as friends?
It is. Yeah.
Yeah.
l really hit rock
bottom that night.
And l mean that
1 literally fell
to the bottom of
a pit and hit a rock.
l remember
laying there thinking,
"There's probably a good
reason why l'm down
here and single."
And then | started thinking,
"| need morphine."
Oh, yeah, | hear you made
two male penguins
very happy today.
You're making history,
Knope. | like that.
Sticking your
neck out, you know.
No, | didn't stick
my neck out. It was
an accident.
Out of the mainstream.
l think that's cool.
l'm in the mainstream.
Yeah, | know.
No, no. Not out of it.
Social activism.
No! Uh-uh.
People in this
town don't really like
their government
employees being activists.
Last year, a garbage
man was suspended
for wearing
a Live Strong bracelet.
Hey, Leslie, some guy
Who owns a gay bar
sent you a cake.
Pawnee has a gay bar?
Yeah.
The Bulge.
It's behind my house.
The Bulge is a gay bar?
Uh, the nights
l've wasted there.
"Leslie! Hey,
girrrrrrrrl!"
With eight R's.
"Thank you for supporting
the cause of gay marriage.
"You rock!
The boys at The Bulge."
They thought that was
a political gesture?
Okay, nobody eat that cake.
Tom? Step into my office.
That's also my office.
Yeah, whatever.
l know that you are not gay.
No, l'm not.
But you're effeminate.
What?
Well, you're wearing
a peach shirt with
a coiled snake on it.
Yes, 'cause it was featured
in Details magazine.
And it's awesome.
Effeminate.
Anyway, so the point is,
do you think that
marrying penguins
made some kind of statement?
Yes. The statement was
that you're very lonely
and you need a pet.
Huh.
Leslie? They sent
you T-shirts, too.
Oh! Wow, look, they
sentus a T-shirt.
Hmm...
Mine has a collaron it.
There she is.
Leslie!
Hey!
Hey.
This is my boyfriend,
Derek, and this is
Derek's boyfriend, Ben.
Ĥi.
Hey.
Oh! Wait, sorry,
what's the situation?
What do you mean?
Derek is gay,
but he's straight for me,
but he's gay
for Ben, and Ben's
really gay for Derek.
And | hate Ben.
It's not that complicated.
No.
Oh. Yeah. Sure.
The thing about
youth culture is,
l don't understand it.
So what can |
do for you guys?
They just really
wanted to meet you,
because you're kind
of like their hero now.
Oh, oh, April, please,
it was just penguins.
APRIL: No!
l'm a public servant,
and l'm not allowed
to take a political stance.
But you did,
and it was awesome.
Yeah. None of the other
politicians ever
take a stand,
and it means a lot to
the whole gay community.
It does, and we're
gonna have this party
tomorrow night at The Bulge,
and we had
something to ask you.
We really want you to
be the guest of honor.
Oh, my.
Itd be amazing
if you came.
Yeah, you have to come.
Who made this?
We did.
Yeah, we did.
How?
Photoshop.
What? Oh!
Computers.
Hey, why are you
all dolled up?
It's a long story.
l'm the guest of honor
at this gay bar tonight.
l guess gay men are
starting to like me.
l don't know.
l guess they think
l'm fabulous or something.
Well, you look good, girl.
You're gonna turn
somebody tonight.
(LAŬGHING)
That was hands-down
the best interaction
l've ever had with Donna.
Leslie, this is
Marcia Langman from
the Society For Family
Stability Foundation.
Oh, hello.
| love your top.
Oh, thank you so much.
l was just hoping
you had a moment
to discuss the events
at the zoo yesterday.
Well, | have nothing
to do with this, so...
Well, what can | do for
you and those fine
people at the SFSF?
Well, you could resign,
if you're up for it.
Oh, you're serious?
When you performed a marriage
for gay penguins,
using taxpayer money
on government property,
you were symbolically
taking a stand
in favor of
the gay marriage agenda.
Oh, l'm sorry, but hold on
a second there, Marcia.
That was not my
intention, at all.
Well, why else would
you marry penguins?
Because | firmly believed
that it would be cute.
And it was.
Leslie, are you married?
No. Not yet, Marcia.
Soon, probably.
l have a plan,
but, no, not now.
Not dating anyone yet.
Focusing on my career.
l thought so.
So you couldn't
possibly understand,
but when gays marry,
it ruins marriage
for the rest of us.
So, either you
annul the wedding,
or l'll publicly ask
for your resignation.
You know what?
l'm so terrible
with directions.
If l'm headed to
the parking lot,
do | make a left
out of here,
or do | go right?
It's a left, yeah.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Annul the wedding!
(EXHALES)
Hey.
Hi!
l'm supposed to
meet Leslie for lunch,
but she actually works, so...
Ouch!
ANN: Mark was brought to
my hospital the night
of the accident.
He was here for a week.
! think when his
head hit the ground,
it mustve knocked
something loose,
because he's actually
a pretty nice guy now.
And Andy, after we
broke up, he told me
he was going to Kansas
to climb mountains.
So, | don't really
know where he is.
Hey, have you seen
that documentary
about food yet?
No, | haven't.
But | heard it's really
good. | want to see it.
We should go together.
What? Yeah, no. | don't
think so. That would
be like a date.
Okay. Say no more.
Mmm.
l hate salad.
Leslie, | don't
want to ever keep
secrets from you.
Oh, me, neither.
Look, let's invent our own
secret language that
only we understand.
And then we can use
it around people
and no one will know what
we're talking about.
Okay.
But in the meantime,
l'm just gonna
tell you in English.
Mark kind of
asked me out.
He weirdly asked me
to go see a movie with him,
and | said no,
of course, but | just...
l just wanted
to let you know.
l'm feeling a lot
of confusing things
right now.
Yeah. No, of course you are.
And your friendship
is the most important
thing to me.
And he's off-limits.
Thank you. | just want
to let you know, | was
really serious
about that secret language.
l know.
(HIP-HOP SONG PLAYING)
l can't believe
this is a gay bar.
Yeah, especially
with that heterosexual
cowboy greeting
us on the way in.
Where should | drink now?
There's a bar on
Eighth Street called
Pitchers and Catchers.
You can go there.
Yeah. Hey!
Okay, listen.
Here's the plan.
Our position is,
we have no position.
So let's just say,
"Thank you for the party,
"but we regretfully decline
your offer to honor me."
Oh, my God,
| can't believe you came.
Hi, April.
Derek! It's Leslie Knope.
Leslie Knope,
you're my hero!
Oh! That's nice.
Leslie, you are
looking hot.
Really?
Thank you, Ben.
l'm really enjoying this hug.
That's so nice,
but | need to
tell you something.
This one is on Us.
Well, if it's free...
Leslie Knope!
(ALL CHEERING)
She's Leslie Knope,
and she wants to recruit you!
No, no, no. Oh, my.
Okay. Please,
please, please, please.
Gentlemen. First of all,
I would just like to say
thank you so much
for throwing me this party,
especially on a night
when the Colts are playing.
We love you, Leslie!
Okay.
This is green.
(ALL CHEERING LOUDLY)
ALL: Leslie! Leslie!
Leslie! Leslie! Leslie!
Leslie! Leslie!
Okay! Well, I wanted
to tell you
that l wasn't really
trying to take a stand
when | married
those penguins.
Leslie! Leslie! Leslie!
You're chanting my name.
Leslie! Leslie!
Leslie! Leslie! Leslie!
1 just have one thing
to say! Together we can
change Pawnee forever!
Let's dance!
(HIP-HOP SONG PLAYING)
Leslie Knope's in
the building, y'all!
Let's get wild!
l've seen so many
dudes from City Hall
here tonight, it's crazy.
But | guess they've
seen me here, too.
So, that's not great.
Hey! Hi. I got your text.
Is everything okay?
Oh, yeah! They're having
a party in my honor!
Go to the bar.
If you're my friend,
you can drink for free!
Oh! Cool! Okay,
and maybe next time
don't use the words
"medical emergency."
l'm so glad you're here!
l'm really sober!
Okay! Get a drink!
(MOUTHING WORDS)
You know why tonight's fun?
"Cause everyone's so gay.
And they know
how to have fun,
and the dancing!
Just, it's... Everyone
is just who they are.
And who they are is
just stone-cold gay.
(SINGING) Can't read my
Can't read my
No, he can't read
my poker face
Blah, blah, blah, blah
My, my, my, poker face
My, my poker face
l'm having such
a nice time tonight.
l've met many
interesting people.
And there's two
bisexual guys here,
and | got both of
their phone numbers.
(SINGING) My, my,
my poker face
My, my poker face
My, my, my poker face
The whole morning.
Show me what's hot
Tell me what | got
Can't read my
Can't read my...
Have fun last night?
l had three
drinks named after me,
so that's pretty fun.
Plus, Ben and Derek
are taking me
shopping on Saturday.
And we are gonna find out
my actual bra size.
l guess l'm kind of
like queen of the gays.
Bully for you.
I just got a phone call.
They want you to
go on Pawnee Today.
Wow. That's huge.
What's the topic?
You.
That Marcia Langman
from the family thing
is calling for
your resignation.
No!
You gotta go on
and defend yourself.
Why? | haven't even
officially taken a stand
on gay marriage.
That's funny.
Somebody just told me
you were queen of the gays.
That was me.
Pawnee Today,
with Joan Callamezzo.
It's kind of like
the Meet the Press
of our town.
It's the big time, Leslie.
Yeah, | know.
It is. l'm nervous.
l just wish | were here
under different circumstances.
Guess who?
Uh... Megan Fox?
One of
the Desperate Housewives?
No, Joan Callamezzo.
Hey, Joanie!
What's up, gorgeous?
Good to see you.
Tom comes on
the show all the time.
Joan loves him.
You have the softest skin
of any woman in Pawnee.
Thank you.
l wish you could reach,
from your TV screen,
and just touch
Joan's skin for a second.
That's sweet.
You'd have a treat.
You're pretty
soft yourself.
How are your
kids doing?
They're pretty good.
Is it tough for
them to have a mother
that is so beautiful?
What's it like being
the most attractive
woman in Pawnee?
You keep up those funnies,
l'm gonna have to
invite you over for supper.
Well, l'll have to
come over for supper.
(GIGGLING)
Oh! You must.
Oh, my God.
Ann Perkins.
How you doing?
l'm good. How was
mountain climbing?
(EXCLAIMS)
What?
(CHUCKLES NERVOUSLY)
Can | come in?
l just want to talk
to you for a second.
Sure, yeah.
JOAN: We have a controversial
topic today, the gay penguin
marriage at the Pawnee Zoo.
So, Marcia, what is
all the fuss about?
The fuss is that
Miss Knope claimed that
she was not
advocating for
this gay cause,
and then that very night,
she was the guest of honor
at a pro-gay marriage rally
at a bar called The Bulge.
Miss Knope,
how do you respond?
l'd first like to say
that | wasn't trying to
advocate for anyone.
l did not know that
both of the penguins
were males,
and | was just trying
to perform a cute,
fun ceremony to
promote our local zoo.
| have to say that
that stunt that you did
with the penguins was
clearly over the line.
Now, Marcia, what, if
anything, can Miss Knope
do to make it right?
Joan, we don't want
to be unreasonable.
Of course not.
We think that she should
separate the penguins,
annul the marriage,
reimburse the taxpayers
for the cost of the wedding,
of course,
and then resign.
Oh! ls that it?
That would do it.
Anything else?
You want me to
jump off a building?
Perform hara-kiri?
Move to a different town?
No, | kid.
Full of ideas here today.
This is the reason
why people don't
go into politics.
Because, | bust my ass
for the people in this city,
and | can't win.
l have one night of fun
with some of the best dancers
l've ever danced with,
and suddenly everybody's
freaking out?
Wow, look at that!
Wow, we're lighting up here.
Great. Let's go for it.
Bring it on.
l've never seen that
on our show before.
How does this work?
Well, there...
Push that, and...
Great. Okay. Hey!
You're on the air!
You're on the air! Good!
CALLER 1: Yeah, l think that
lady should resign.
Okay, good.
Thank you. Next caller.
CALLER 1: You should resign
and repay your salary.
Okay, two for resign.
Thank you. Next caller.
CALLER 2: / just want to
say that I love the zoo,
and the zoo is really fun.
Thank you.
That's really sweet.
And l think you
should resign.
You look great.
You look amazing.
Thanks. You look fancy.
Oh, yeah, the monkey suit.
Cost 3,000 bucks,
but totally worth it.
l sold out!
l got a boring
office job in town, so...
l gotta dress up,
you know, the grind.
But l'm really happy,
and | really feel
like l've matured a lot.
Good! That's...
l'm happy for you.
Yeah.
So listen, | was
sitting in the cubicle
the other day,
just doing some thinking,
and some growing...
And some maturing.
(CHUCKLES) Yes! Maturing.
And darn itif l don't
just miss you, and...
Andy.
Well, A-Cakes, just let me...
l love you,
and l'm just really
sorry for the way
that | treated you.
l was the worst
boyfriend ever,
l know that,
and | really think
it would behoove us
to give it another shot.
Yeah, look.
l'm really happy for
you about your job
and that you've
learned some new words,
but l'm sure
about my decision.
Okay. Say no more.
ANDY: Listen, hit me up
on my cell phone.
lH be around.
And if you wanna talk,
or grab coffee or
something like that.
Okay?
ANN: Okay.
Oh. Gotta get back
to the office.
Have a good one.
Good seeing you.
Bye.
And the hardest part
about living in this pit
is probably keeping
my suit pressed.
And the rats.
It's like a freaking
rat parade every night.
l just want to be
close to her house,
because | need
to protect her.
"Cause there are
some weird people
that live around here.
CALLER 3: Yeah, if you let
penguins get married,
where does it end?
! mean, would you let me
marry my guinea pig?
Because | really do
want to marry my guinea pig.
TI take my answer
off the air.
l think that's
a valuable point.
Attendance is up 3090
at the zoo, by the way.
You're welcome.
That penguin wedding was
cute, damn it. And l'm
not gonna annul it.
l'd ask you to reconsider.
Well, l'd ask you
to stop asking me,
because it's not
gonna happen, Marcia.
Is that right?
Last time | checked,
l don't think l
murdered anyone,
or had an affair,
or did drugs!
But | apologize.
l apologize for having fun,
and for making
something cute!
Where are you
from originally?
Oh, no!
What did | do?
So, you will not be
annulling the marriage?
No. | will not
be annulling. No.
Look at them. They're just
in their own little
penguin love bubble.
l guess that's what it's like
when you meet your mate
and know you're gonna
be together forever.
(DOORBELL RINGING)
Hi!
You know what | realized?
What?
We're just animals.
We don't know
anything about love.
Okay.
Yeah.
l think you should go
on that date with Mark.
Oh, Leslie...
Really, seriously.
| thought about it,
and, look, he might
not be my gay penguin,
but he could be yours.
Look, | told you
l'm not going on
a date with him.
Okay, fine. If you don't
want to go out with him,
don't go out with him.
But don't not do
it because of me,
because l'm
really fine with it.
All that's important to me
is that we're still friends.
Me, too!
Good! Great.
Plus, l already called him
and told him that
you were dying to go out
with him, so have fun.
Huh?
So, | transferred
the penguins to
a zoo in lowa.
Gay marriage is legal there,
so hopefully,
they'll be happy.
At least they'll be together.
Oh, look! Six Flags!
l should take them
on a water slide.
They might die.
But it would be so cute!